(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-23T01:09:25.556935",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
同じ未来を見たいの
I want to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
I want that dream in my hands.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo
Running with our respective hearts, let's go!
Shiny Smily Story (2022 ver.)
[Song: Shiny Smily Story (2022 ver.)]
みんな今日はAZKi活動4周年ライブ来てくれてありがとう！盛り上がっていこう！
Everyone, thank you for coming to AZKi's 4th anniversary live today! Let's get hyped up!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
No matter where I looked, it sprouted in a pitch-dark place,
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
and my eyes were stolen by just a tiny hope.
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning my heart that trembles with anxiety,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I was mustering up just a tiny bit of courage.
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting the word "give up" and moving forward,
苦しいときも、もう私はひとりじゃないから
even when things are tough, I'm no longer alone.
だからもっと夢追いかけたい
That's why I want to chase my dreams even more,
ワクワク止まらない想像超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world beyond imagination where excitement never stops!
アクセスしてみたい後悔なんてそうさせない
I want to access it, and I won't let there be any regrets.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo
Running with our respective hearts, let's go!
加速の空に輝く眩しい想いは
The dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たことのない光をリアルに届けるよ
deliver a light never seen before into reality.
いつも聴こえるエールはここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers I always hear right here,
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
it makes me want to search for a new light once again.
君の笑顔は保存して進む
Saving your smile as I move forward,
悲しいときに見返すよ力が湧くから
I look back at it when I'm sad, because it gives me strength.
胸を張って夢追いかけたい
Standing proud, I want to chase my dreams.
奇跡のストーリー一緒に作ろう終わらない夢を
Let's create a miraculous story together, an endless dream
誰一人欠かせない愛が舞ったこの世界
in this world where love dances, with not a single person missing.
それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
Painted with our respective hearts,
悲しいときも寂しいときもある
whether there are times of sadness or loneliness,
信じ合えるものがある忘れずにこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい
there is something we can believe in, and I want to keep beating this pulse without forgetting.
終わらない世界に溢れ出る笑顔達憧れの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams amidst the smiles overflowing into an endless world.
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
I want to hold that dream.
それぞれ違ったココロで逢えるものがある
There's something we can find with our unique hearts.
忘れずにこのココロを鳴らし続けていたい
I want to keep ringing this heart without forgetting.
終わらない世界に溢れ出すよ笑顔たち
Smiles overflow into a never-ending world!
憧れの舞台立ちたい 正しく輝きたい
I want to stand on my dream stage and shine brightly,
時に涙して また笑い合いたい
shedding tears at times, and smiling together again.
同じ未来を見たいあの夢手にしたい
I want to see the same future and hold that dream.
踏み出そう奇跡の光を
Let's step forward into the light of miracles!
息切らして夢を追いかけたい
Out of breath, I want to chase my dreams.
ワクワクと止まらない高鳴りを超えてく
Surpassing the thrilling, endless heartbeat,
世界に見せてあげる
I'll show it to the world!
アクセスしてみてみない？
Why don't you try accessing it?
後悔なんてことにない それぞれで違った
There's no regret, everyone is different.
ココロでつくるわ
We create it with our hearts.
みんな、こんばあずき！
Everyone, good evening Azki!
本日はAZKi活動4周年記念ライブ、王座アニバーサリーライブページーズにお越しいただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for attending AZKi's 4th Anniversary Live, "Oza Anniversary Live: Pages"!
まあ、コメントもたくさんありがとう！
Thank you so much for all the comments too!
お祝いのコメントもみんなありがとうございます！
Thank you all for the congratulatory messages as well!
そして、事前にも告知している通り、本日は新ビジュアルをお披露目します！
And as announced in advance, today we are revealing a new visual!
ということで、ぜひ最後まで見ていってください！
With that said, please be sure to watch until the very end!
ということで、1曲目は「Shiny Smily Story (2022 ver.)」をお届けしました！
So, our first song was "Shiny Smily Story (2022 ver.)"!
そして今日はアイドル衣装で、1曲目を歌いましたけれども、
And today I sang the first song in my idol costume, but...
なんでこの曲を1曲目にしたかというと、AZKiホロライブに移籍して、
why did I make this song the first one? Ever since AZKi transferred to Hololive,
からですね、約半年が経ちまして、この曲で今日は始めたいと思って歌わせていただきました。
about half a year has passed, and I wanted to start today with this song.
ということで、もう4周年ですね！
So, it's already the 4th anniversary!
4年ってすごい月日ですね。だってこれから、
Four years is an amazing amount of time. Because going forward,
ま、5年目ということで、いや、まさかまさか、
entering our 5th year... I never, ever thought
こうやって今日を迎えられたことに、みんなに感謝したいと思います。
that we'd be able to welcome today like this, and I want to thank everyone.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
2022年はですね、本当にいろんなことがありました。
In 2022, truly a lot of things happened.
ちょっと改めてここで振り返ってみますと、2021年ですね、12月に、インナミュージックのプロジェクトが終了しまして、
Looking back on it here, in December 2021, Inonaka Music's project ended,
2022年4月にホロライブに所属することになりました。
and in April 2022, I joined Hololive.
もともと、AZKiはですね、インナミュージックの活動、
Originally, AZKi's activities in Inonaka Music,
イコールAZKiのプロジェクト自体が、今年の7月に終わるはずだった世界にいたんですけれども、
meaning AZKi's project itself was supposed to end this July in the world it was in, but...
今日ここで、11月15日歌っているAZKiがいる世界にみんなに連れてきてもらいました。
today here, everyone brought me to a world where AZKi is singing on November 15th.
それが本当に良かったのか、悪かったのか、楽しかったのか、正しくなかったのか分からないですけれども、
Whether that was truly good or bad, fun or not right, I don't know, but...
でも今日こうやってコメントで応援してくれたりしてくれるみんなが、開拓者のみんながいるだと、AZKiは...
but today, seeing everyone cheering for me in the comments, and knowing the pioneers are here, AZKi...
したり、悲しいことも悔しいこともたくさんありました。
There were many sad and frustrating moments.
あの、
Um,
でも、そういう、あの積み重ねの中で、えっと、今日はね、新しいスタッフの皆さんにも囲まれて、え、今日のこのライブができています。
Through all of those accumulated experiences, today, surrounded by new staff members, I'm able to hold this live concert.
ありがとう。みんながいてくれ、宝物です。ありがとう。
Thank you. Having you all here is my treasure. Thank you.
え、4年間、そして、また、これですね、ま、いろんな、みんなもね、いろんな出会いと別れを、あの、たくさんあると思うんですけど、まあ、その中で、AZKiの歌や音楽が、みんなの心に届いたら、いいなって思ってます。
Um, over these four years, and moving forward, I'm sure everyone experiences many encounters and partings. Through all of that, I hope AZKi's songs and music reach everyone's hearts.
はい、ちょっと、真剣な話を、初めの話をして、ちょっと、いろいろと思い出したところがありましてけど、
Yes, starting with a serious talk made me remember a lot of things, but...
でも、今日は、え、嬉しいこと、新ビジュアルのお披露目、そして、最後には告知もある、みたいななので、
Today, we have happy news, the debut of my new visual, and announcements at the end, so
最後まで楽しんでいってください！
please enjoy it all the way to the end!
それでは、ちょっとね、アイドル衣装から、いつも着ている、普段の衣装にチェンジしたいと思います！
Now, I'd like to change from my idol outfit into my usual everyday outfit!
さっ、
Here
we go!
早着替え、早着替えしてきました！
I did a quick change!
はい、ちょっとお水飲んでいいですか？お水飲みます。
Right, may I have a sip of water? I'll drink some water.
はい、では、ですね、ま、そんないろんな思いを、あの、込めて、今日は歌って、いきたいと思います。
Right, then... putting all those feelings into it, I'd like to sing for you today.
それでは、次の曲、聞いてください。
Now, please listen to the next song.
青い夢。
"Blue Dream."
あなたのおかげで 私が居る
"Because of you, I am here."
聴いてくれたことに 価値がある
There is value in you listening to me.
綺麗事に隠された 本音が建前の隙間をすり抜けた
The true feelings hidden behind nice words slipped through the gaps of pretense.
腫れ物みたいに扱わないで 本音をどうこう隠そうとしないで
Don't treat me like a sore thumb, don't try to hide my true feelings.
一番欲しいのは 誰かのエールか？
Is what I want most someone's cheers?
たったそれだけじゃ 食い繋ぎえない
Just that alone isn't enough to survive.
愛が君を救えるなら 音楽はいらないさ
If love can save you, music is unnecessary.
夢だけで私は 生き続けられない
I cannot keep living on dreams alone.
誰も間違ってはいないから
Because no one is wrong.
正論に押し潰されて 息苦しいだろう
Crushed by logical arguments, it must be suffocating.
弱さを許せば 喜ばれる
If you allow weakness, people are pleased.
個性を歌えば 支持を得られる
If you sing of individuality, you gain support.
名無しの感情を切り裂いて 対価を欲しがるのが怖いのは
Tearing apart nameless emotions, why is it scary to desire a reward?
一番大事なのは 私の想いか？
Is my own feeling the most important thing?
「君、変わったね。」って言われてしまうね
"You've changed," people might say.
青くなり切れずに 中途半端に大人で嫌になりそうだよ
Unable to stay purely naive, half-grown into an adult, it's frustrating.
愛が君を救えるなら 音楽はいらないさ
If love can save you, music is unnecessary.
夢だけで私は 生き続けられない
I cannot keep living on dreams alone.
誰も間違ってはいないから
Because no one is wrong.
守れない日を
Days I cannot protect
君かわったねって言われちゃうね 青くなりきれずに中途半端に大人で嫌になりそうだよ
"You've changed," they say, half-grown and unrefined, it makes me sick.
愛が君を救えるなら 音楽はいらないさ
If love can save you, music is unnecessary.
夢だけで私は 生き続けられない
I cannot keep living on dreams alone.
誰も間違ってはいないから
Because no one is wrong.
正論に押し潰されて
Crushed by logical arguments,
誰一人 誰も間違ってはいないから
Not a single person is wrong, so
正論に押し潰されて
crushed by logical arguments,
でも逃げないよ
but I won't run away.
夢だから
Because it's a dream.
息をしている 君は生きている
Breathing, you are alive.
当然のこと 誰も疑わないの
It's natural; no one doubts it.
息をしている ように見えている
It looks like you're breathing.
生の裏側 私にとっての何か
What is the flip side of life to me?
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat is pounding heavily.
叩かれても腐らずに 此処で歌うよ
Even if beaten down, without rotting, I'll sing right here.
ボタン一つの いのち
A single button's life.
最後まで私のこと 覚えててくれるの？
Will you remember me until the very end?
消してしまいそうなの わかってよ わかってよ ねぇ
It feels like it's going to fade away—understand, understand, hey!
本当のとこなの？恋と推しは違うんでしょ？
Is that really true? Love and being a fan are different, right?
君が忘れちゃったら 私は居なくなるの
If you forget me, I will disappear.
命のような夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life.
またね、バイバイ。
See you later, bye-bye.
息をしている だから生きている
Breathing, therefore I'm alive.
自己証明を欲しがって 欲しがっているんだ
Desiring, yearning for self-proof.
音が止まって 動かなくなって
When the sound stops and movement ceases,
そんな私を 君は笑ってくれるかな
will you smile at someone like me?
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat is pounding heavily.
嫌われても腐らずに 此処で歌うよ
Even if hated, without rotting, I'll sing right here.
気分次第の いのち
A life depending on my mood.
最後まで私のこと 見届けてくれるの？
Will you watch over me until the very end?
覚めてしまいそうなの わかってよ わかってよ ねぇ
It feels like I'm waking up—understand, understand, hey!
声が聴こえるんだよ 塩辛い涙が出ちゃうほど
I can hear your voice, to the point where salty tears come out.
君が忘れちゃったら 私は居なくなるの
If you forget me, I will disappear.
命のような夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life.
またね、バイバイ。
See you later, bye-bye.
ふさぎこんだあの日を 軽くイジらないで やめて それが生きる糧になるから
Don't lightly poke at that gloomy day—stop it, because that becomes my nourishment to live.
大丈夫 ずっと私は 歌い続けるから
It's okay, I will keep on singing forever.
最後まで私も生きているか わからないけど
I don't know if I'll be alive until the very end, but
君がくれた言葉は 確実に残ってる
the words you gave me definitely remain.
最後まで私のこと 覚えててくれるの？
Will you remember me until the very end?
いつ死んでしまうだろう わかんない わかんないよ ねぇ
When will I die? I don't know, I don't know, hey!
痛いくらい気持ちが シンクロする時もあるけど
Sometimes our feelings synchronize to a painful degree, but
君が忘れちゃったら 私は居なくなるの
if you forget me, I will disappear.
命のような夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life.
またね、バイバイ。
See you later, bye-bye.
そう見つけた この先だけの世界を
I found the world just ahead...
止まりかけていた 時を進めるための
that was about to stop, to move time forward.
こんなはずじゃなかった 不意に漏れた言葉さえ
It wasn't supposed to be like this—even the words that slipped out
あんな日もよかった そう思える君がいるよ
were fine days after all, knowing you're here.
消えかけても 見えなくても ここに私は居る
Even if I fade away, even if I'm invisible, I'm right here.
暗闇の世界さえ 越えてく光を
Crossing even the world of darkness with light.
間違っても 無くなっても 僕の選ぶ世界
Even if I make mistakes, even if it's lost, this is the world I choose.
想い描いた花じゃなくたって この種 咲かすよ
Even if it's not the flower I envisioned, I will make this seed bloom.
ああ見つけた 失いかけていた僕の座標
Ah, I found the coordinates I was about to lose.
エンドロールには 早すぎると気づいた
I realized it was too early for the end roll.
僕だけじゃないんだ 気づけばそばに居たんだ
I'm not the only one; before I knew it, you were right by my side.
足跡は続く ほら聴こえる次の音が
Footprints continue—listen, the next sound is audible.
届かなくても 憧れの背に 少しだけ追い付けた
Even if it doesn't reach, I caught up just a little to the back of my yearning.
花と咲くその日まで 想いを歌うよ
Until the day it blooms like a flower, I will sing my feelings.
途切れかけた糸も また繋がる そんな世界があるよ
A frayed thread connects once more; such a world exists.
次の夜空に光る 星々に希望を託そう
Let's entrust our hopes to the stars shining in the next night sky.
こんな世界 こんな未来 僕らの地図になかった
Such a world, such a future—was never on our map.
約束できないよ こんな素敵な未来 想像できないから
I can't promise such a wonderful future, because I can't even imagine it.
消えかけても 見えなくても 何度くじけても
Even if it fades, even if it's invisible, no matter how many times I stumble...
足跡の伸びる先 未来が続くよ
where my footprints extend, the future continues.
そう間違っても 無くなっても 何度でも作ろう
Yes, even if we make mistakes, even if it's lost, we'll create it over and over.
行く先を失くしても 君となら探せるよ 上書きの地図を広げて 僕らの世界で
Even if I lose my way, with you I can find it—expanding the overwritten map in our world.
もう行かなくちゃいけない
I have to go now,
永く遠い道の終わり
at the end of a long and distant road.
静かに眠った おでこを合わせて
Sleeping quietly, pressing our foreheads together,
深く息をした
I breathed in deeply.
見上げた先には 赤い空
Looking up, there was a red sky.
きっと同じ空を見ているのかな
Are you surely looking at the same sky?
胸に残る
Remaining in my heart,
あなたのあなたのあなたの声が 今
your, your, your voice now...
夢に落ちて
falling into a dream.
夢で覚める
Waking up from a dream,
あなたのあなたのあなたの記憶 今
your, your, your memories now...
私を置いていく
leaving me behind.
ほら幸せなことは
See, happy things
すぐに消えてしまうようで
seem to disappear so quickly,
あんなに好きだった 景色も
and the scenery I loved so much,
音楽も 色褪せてしまった
and the music too, have faded away.
今を生きていくこと
Living in the present moment,
一人ひたすら走ること
running on all alone,
私という存在は 脆くて
my existence is so fragile,
その足音がない
and its footsteps are gone.
見上げた先には 灰の空
Looking up, there is an ash-gray sky,
ちゃんと色を取り戻せるように
so that I can properly regain its colors.
世界の真ん中
In the middle of the world,
あなたのあなたのあなたの声が 今こだまする
your, your, your voice now echoes.
世界のどこか
Somewhere in the world,
あなたのあなたのあなたの欠片 今
your, your, your fragments now...
私は探している
I am searching for them.
胸に残る
Remaining in my heart,
数多の数多のあなたの声が 今
countless, countless voices of yours now...
空に溶けていく
melt into the sky.
夢で覚める
Waking up from a dream,
数多の数多のあなたの記憶 今
countless, countless memories of yours now...
私を忘れていく
are forgetting me.
きっと良かった
I'm sure it was for the best,
これで最後
this is the very end.
もう行かなくちゃ
I have to go now.
最後...
Finally...
もういいから 口を...
That's enough, keep your mouth...
夢が終わる
The dream ends.
ということで、青い夢、命、オーバーライト、afterglowお届けしました！
And with that, we delivered Aoi Yume,
Inochi, Overwrite, and afterglow!
そして、皆さんお待たせしました！AZKi新ビジュアルお披露目でーす！
And everyone, thanks for waiting!
It's the unveiling of AZKi's new visual!
いかがでしょうか？
How is it?
いかがでしょうか？いかがでしょうか？
How is it? How is it?
あ、たくさん拍手ありがとう！
Ah, thank you so much for the applause!
はい。そして、衣装チェンジのね、タイミングで、えー、これまでの、えー、ファースト、セカンド、サードの衣装までの奇跡をまとめた映像も作っていただきまして、
Yes. And at the timing of the costume change,
they made a video compiling the journey up to...
どうでしたか？なんか、うっ、うってきましたね(笑)。
How was it? It sort of made me choke up.
ちょっと涙が出そうになるくらいすごく素敵にこれまでのAZKiの衣装とかもそうですし、
It's so wonderful, almost making me want to cry—
not only AZKi's past costumes,
MVがね、後ろにね、あの、流れていたんですけど...
but also the music video was playing in the back...
はい、そんな、えー、奇跡を歴史を経て、今日、えー、新ビジュアルとなりました！みんなありがとう！
Yes, after going through such history and miracles,
today we have our new visual! Thank you everyone!
はい、じゃあちょっともっと細く見てもらいたいなと思うので、ちょっとライブ用のこのマイク置いてきますね。
Yes, I'd like you to look at it in more detail,
so I'll put down this live microphone.
はい、ということで、えー、今回の、えー、新ビジュアルのコンセプトはズバリ、アーティストなAZKiです！(笑)
Yes, with that said, the concept for this new visual
is precisely: an artistic AZKi!
今までもすごい、あの、攻めた衣装だったり、あの、サード衣装はすごくね、ステージ衣装という感じで、に、推したてしていただいてたんですけれど、
Up until now we've had very bold costumes,
and the third costume was heavily promoted as a stage costume...
今回はなんかこうアーティストな、ちょっと大人びたAZKiということで、
this time, it's an artistic, somewhat more mature AZKi.
えー、今回デザインはスコッティさん、そしてモデリングは、えー、我らがパパ、加速パパ、加速佐藤さんに推したていただきましたーー！
This time the design was created by Scotty-san,
and modeling was done by our dad, Kasoku Satou-san!
はい、じゃあ細かくみんな、細かく見ていきますか？お披露目だからね？お披露目なのだね。
Shall we look closely at the details, everyone?
Since it's an unveiling!
はい、まず、えー、髪型、変えました！
Yes, first, I changed my hairstyle!
どうですか？髪型ロングになりましたよ！
How is it? My hair has become long!
ロングといえばファースト、ファースト衣装のときもロングではあったけれども、
Speaking of long hair, my first costume
had long hair too, but...
えー、ちょっとこういった、なんかね、ちょっと編み込みが、ここね、ここここここここ、編み込みがあって、後ろでね、こう結んでおりますけれども、
there's a braid right here, right here,
and it's tied up like this in the back.
えー、ロングになりました！いかがですか？ロングのAZKiは
It became long! How do you like long-haired AZKi?
ロング合ってる？あ、似合ってる？あ、嬉しい！嬉しい！
Does long hair suit me? Ah, it suits me?
Ah, I'm so happy!
そうだね、ちょっと今までショートというか短い髪型だったので、えー、今回はロングのAZKi。
That's right, until now I've had short hair,
so this time it's long-haired AZKi.
そう、ポニーテールっぽい後ろね、ここね。
Yes, a ponytail-like back, right here.
はい、に、えー、推したていただきまして、そして、えー、AZKi今までは結構黒の、ね、衣装とか、あのサード衣装はもうピンク！アイドル！っていうような衣装だったんですけれど、
Up until now AZKi's costumes were quite black,
or the third costume was pink! Idol-like!
今回は白をね、基調として、そう、あ、カメラさんありがとうございます！
This time, based mainly on white—
ah, thank you camera-san!
えー、白を基調とした、えー、ここが、えっとね、ワンピースっぽくなっておりまして、
Based on white, um,
this part has become like a one-piece dress,
そして、えー、ブラウスに、ここの、ここの、ここのブラウスに大きいリボン、リボンがついており、ここにちゃんとアクセサリーもついており、
and on the blouse, right here,
there's a big ribbon, and proper accessories too,
そしてね、スカートね、こちらを、下から、下から...えー、スカートが実は二色、こうね、あの、左右非対称なんですよ。これは何て言うんですか？アシンメトリーですか？
and the skirt is actually two-toned,
and asymmetrical on left and right. What is this?
えー、このね、左右が非対称な、実態は、あの、色がピンクとちょっとグレーというね、二色な、あの、ワンピーススカートになっております！はい。
This left-right asymmetry, actually,
the colors are pink and a bit of gray!
そしてそして、えー、そうだな、アクセサリーも紹介しよう。
And then, let's also introduce the accessories.
この髪の、ね、ここはAZKiの、あの今までの衣装の中にも、あのずっと大事に取り入れたい色として、このね、こうグリーンの色とAZKiのこの赤とピンク系のちょっとアクセサリーを、あのね、つけてもらいました、作ってもらいました！
This green color and red-to-pink-toned accessories—
I had them made and put on for me!
いいでしょ、いいでしょ。
Isn't it nice? Isn't it?
そう、ちゃんと、今までのもモチーフとかもちょっと入れたいなと思ってこんな感じにアクセサリーを作ってもらいました。
I wanted to incorporate some motifs from my past designs, so I had them make accessories like this.
そして、そう、なんかちゃんとね、今回はこのブレスレットとかも結構編みって、すごい、ピカピカ。
And also, this time, even things like this bracelet are braided intricately—it's so sparkly!
もうすごく細かく作ってもらっていて、このAZKiのこのヘアアクセサリーと実物はこう形がね一緒だったり細かいところまで作っていただいております。
They made it in such fine detail, and this hair accessory of mine actually shares the same shape down to the smallest parts.
そしてネイルもちゃんとしておりますよ。おしゃれなネイルもしてありますよ。ありますよということで綺麗でしょ。綺麗。あ、綺麗綺麗。ありがとうございます。
And my nails are done properly too! I've got stylish nails as well. Aren't they pretty? Pretty! Oh, pretty, pretty. Thank you very much.
そしてですね、あとはなんだろ、あと紹介し、ヘア、ヘア後ろはねこのお花っぽいヘアアクセサリーとなっております。はい。
And then, what else? The back of my hair has this flower-like hair accessory. Yep.
どうですか？みんな。あ、そうそう。今日言うの忘れてた。このあのAZKi新ビジュアルお披露目でみんなスクショを撮って、
How is it, everyone? Oh right! I forgot to mention today. Please take screenshots of AZKi's new visual reveal,
スクショを撮ってあげてください。ツイート、ツイートしてください！
and share them. Please tweet them!
みんななんかしてほしいポーズありますか？ありますか？
Does everyone have any poses you want me to do? Do you?
はい。なんだろう、でもなんかアーティストっぽい感じにね、そう、したいと思っていたんで、アーティストっぽい、アーティストっぽい立ち振る舞いてどうなんですかね？
Yeah. I wanted it to feel kind of artist-like, so how does an artist-like demeanor go?
こ、こ、こ、こんな感じ？こ、こんな感じですかね？こんな感じ？違うな。
Like this? Is it like this? Like this? No, that's not it.
くるっと回る？くるっと回る。はい、くるっと回りますよ。
Spin around? Spin around. Yep, I'll spin around.
どうですか？どうですか？はい。あ、みんな、あ、かわいい。ありがとうございます。
How is it? How is it? Yeah. Ah, everyone, ah, cute. Thank you.
振り向きのポーズか。こう、こう、どう？どう？こんな感じどうですか？どうですか？
A looking-back pose? Like this, like this, how? How? How's this? How is it?
いいですか？振り向きのポーズ。あ、ありがとうみんな。パシャパシャパシャ、パシャパシャパシャパシャ。はい。
Is this good? A looking-back pose. Ah, thanks everyone. Click, click, click, click, click, click, click. Yep.
ということで、ちょっともう一つ、ちょっとみんなに見せたいものがありまして、なんとこのね、ジャケットなんですけれども、ちょっと脱げます。脱いでいきます。
So, there's one more thing I want to show everyone—turns out, this jacket here... I can take it off. I'm going to take it off.
はい！じつは隠してました！
Ta-da! Actually, I was hiding it!
こちらにリボンが、え、じつは、あのね、こうワンピース、このね、腰のところにリボンをつけていただいております！
Over here, there's a ribbon—well actually, um, a one-piece dress, with a ribbon attached right at the waist!
かわいい！かわいいでしょ？かわいいでしょ？
So cute! Isn't it cute? Isn't it?
そう、スカート後ろめとこっか。こんな感じ。こんな感じになっております。かわいい。そう、身軽になった。
Let's check the back of the skirt. Like this. This is how it looks. Cute. Yeah, I've become light on my feet.
そして、この素敵なデザインの、みなさん、三面図も入手いたしました！こちらです！
And everyone, I've also obtained the three-view design sheet for this wonderful design! Here it is!
お、こちらです！なんとスコッティさんが細かいところまでお仕立てしてしてくださいましたー！
Oh, here it is! Scotty-san tailored it down to the tiniest details!
あとでねTwitterにもあげるのでぜひファードとかAZKiあとで書いてもらえたら嬉しいなって思います。はい、こんな感じね。
I'll post it on Twitter later, so I'd be super happy if you guys could tweet fanart or write about AZKi later. Yep, something like this.
いやあ、細かいところ結構ね、いろいろスコッティさんとねり、ねりねりしながら今回AZKiも、あの衣装のデザインを、ちょっと一緒に悩みながら、あ、どうしようかな、どうしようかなって一緒に考えて、
Man, going over every little detail while hashing things out with Scotty-san... AZKi also helped think through the costume design together, worrying about what to do,
今日はこの衣装ができております。はい。いかがですか？みんな気に入ってくれた？
and today this outfit is complete. Yep. How is it? Did you all like it?
はい、ということで、みんな余すところなく見ていただけましたか？AZKiの新衣装。
Yep, so, did you all get to see AZKi's new outfit to your heart's content?
はい、ということで、この衣装で、ライブの続きをしていきたいと思いますので、ちょっとライブ用のマイクを取ってきまーす！
Yep, so with this outfit, I'd like to continue with the live stream, so I'm going to go grab my live microphone!
はーい！あ、ちょっとジャケットも切れてきて。はい、みんなコメントありがとう！
Hii! Ah, I put the jacket back on too. Yep, thanks everyone for the comments!
はい、ということで、まーだまだライブは後半戦ということで、えーそれではこのあとは今年リリースした、えーAZKiが作詞作曲にも関わった楽曲を今日は歌っていきたいと思います。ちょっと待って、水飲む。
Yep, so the live is still in the second half, so... um, after this, I'd like to sing songs released this year that AZKi was involved in writing and composing. Wait a second, let me drink some water.
はい、ということで、では今年リリースした曲たちを聞いてもらいたいと思います。
Yep, so, I'd like you to listen to the songs I released this year.
それでは聞いてください、
Now then, please listen.
petrichor
今、雨降る、止む
Now, rain falls, stops,
朝、夜手を、手に
Morning, night, hand in hand,
君に届け
Deliver it to you.
今、雨降る、止む
Now, rain falls, stops,
朝、夜手を、手に
Morning, night, hand in hand,
愛している、と
I love you, so...
雨の夜に映る君が
You, reflected in the rainy night,
何を見ていたかわからない
I don't know what you were looking at.
でもね、その瞳に
Yet, in those eyes,
映る君は笑ってた
The reflected you was smiling.
移ろう季節が君を奪い去っても
Even if shifting seasons take you away,
僕は向かう
I will head forward.
響いてゆけ朝焼けの産声、
Resonating onward, the birth of the dawn,
呼ばれているこもざした記憶と
A future called by the memories of chrysalis,
空は紡いでいく
The sky weaves them together
君の掌まで
Into the palm of your hand.
ほらもう、変わっている
Look, everything is already changing.
今過去、手に
Now, past into hands,
自由なんて自分から掴んでいくよ
Freedom is something you grasp for yourself.
奪われても新しいものに出会えるから
Even if it's taken, you can meet something new.
今、雨降る、止む
Now, rain falls, stops,
朝、夜手を、手に
Morning, night, hand in hand,
君に届け
Deliver it to you.
今、雨降る、止む
Now, rain falls, stops,
朝、夜手を、手に
Morning, night, hand in hand,
愛している、と
I love you, so...
ゆらゆら動いたこの心どうも
Swaying and moving, this heart somehow...
あたしはあの子になれなかったんだ
I couldn't become that child.
ゆらゆら風吹く連れ去っていく
Swaying, the blowing wind takes it away.
いいないいなあたしはさ何にも持ってなかった
Oh well, oh well, I had nothing after all.
今、雨降る、止む
Now, rain falls, stops,
朝、夜手を、手に
Morning, night, hand in hand,
君に届け
Deliver it to you.
愛している、と
I love you, so...
ゆらゆら動いたこの心どうも
Swaying and moving, this heart somehow...
あたしはあの子になれなかったんだ
I couldn't become that child.
ゆらゆら風吹く連れ去っていく
Swaying, swaying, the wind blows and carries me away.
いいないいなあたしはさ何にも持ってなかった
Oh well, oh well, I had nothing after all.
傾いてる気分を無視した
Ignoring my leaning mood,
今日も無理してあ頑張っちゃうからな
I'm pushing it today and trying hard again.
フレー！わたし！フレー！わたし！すすめるさ
Hooray! Me! Hooray! Me! Keep moving forward!
今すぐに手に入れたいけどお預けかもね
I want to get it right now, but maybe it's on hold?
もしも今叶うなら届けたい
If it comes true right now, I want to deliver it.
きらきら輝けあの星みたいに
Shining brightly like that star,
あの子はわたしになれなかったんだ
Was that child unable to become me?
きらきら顔出す一等星も
Glittering, showing her face, the primary star too,
そうかそうだよねあなたもさずっと一緒だった
That's right, you were always together with me.
ひらり ひらり 変わった
Fluttering, changing,
この 心育った
this heart grew.
わたしは あの男になれなかったんだ
I couldn't become that boy...
ひらり ひらり 季節を 増やしてみる
Fluttering, fluttering, trying to increase the seasons.
そうだ そうだ
That's right, that's right,
わたしは すべて持っている
I have everything.
ゆらり ゆらり 変わった この未来を
Swaying, swaying, this changed future...
わたしは あの男になれなかったんだ
I couldn't become that boy...
ゆらり ゆらり 掴んだ この運命と
Swaying, swaying, with this grasped fate,
生きてみたい みんなとさ
I want to live with everyone.
今を離さないように
So as not to let go of the present.
きみはだれ
Who are you?
照らす
Illuminating...
日に置き忘れた
left behind in the sun,
わたし光 残る跡がある
there are traces of my light remaining.
きみはどこに いると言ったの？
Where did you say you were?
わたしは世界に いると言った
I said I was in the world!
過去それらさえ
Even those past things
見えなかったんだ
couldn't even be seen.
僕がいる意味を 言いたい の
I want to tell you the meaning of my existence.
わたしが生きる すべてあげる
I'll give you everything of my life.
扉を開く 鍵は折れた
The key to open the door is broken.
わたしが生きる すべてを今 教えてあげるから
Now I'll teach you everything of my life.
僕らの存在が 意味を持たなくても
Even if our existence holds no meaning,
明日 にあの日へと 連鎖 、 そう 船 は 出る
chained to tomorrow from that day, yes, the ship sets sail.
ねえ 今 聞こえて た ？
Hey, could you hear it just now?
わたし ここ で 歌う こと だから
Singing right here, that's why
もう 離さ ない や それだけ が 答え だ から
I won't let go anymore, because that's the only answer.
ああ...
Ah...
はい、ということで聴いていただいたのは
Yes, so the three songs you just heard were
petrichor、canopus、equalの3曲でした！
"petrichor", "canopus", and "equal"!
今年はAZKiも作詞作曲を頑張るぞということで作った楽曲たちになります。
This year, AZKi is working hard on songwriting, so these are songs I created.
ぜひぜひ気に入った曲があったら聞いてみてください！
Please check them out if you find one you like!
この後21時から、
Starting at 9:00 PM tonight,
AZKi活動4周年記念グッズが発売されます！
my 4th anniversary merchandise will go on sale!
わあ、すごい綺麗なイラストだ！
Wow, what a gorgeous illustration!
ということで内容は、こちらになります！
So here are the details!
はい、AZKi EP「Pages」、そしてラバーマット、
Right, we have the AZKi EP "Pages," a rubber mat,
そしてロゴアクリルキーホルダー、そしてTシャツ、
a logo acrylic key holder, and a T-shirt,
シチュエーションボイスの記念ボイスと特典ボイスもありますけれども、
along with commemorative and bonus scenario voices,
以上5つのグッズとボイスのセットになります！
making a set of five goods and voice packs!
さらに、フルセットには、複製特製…あ、違う、複製メッセージ入り、
Furthermore, the full set comes with a replicated special... ah no, a replicated message
チェキ先生の描き下ろしポストカードがついております！
postcard newly illustrated by Chee-sensei!
メッセージは届いてからのお楽しみです。
The message will be a surprise until it arrives.
そして、数量限定にはなりますが、こちらのフルセット、
And while quantities are limited,
お買い上げいただきますと、えっと、AZKiの直筆サインが入っております！
if you purchase this full set, it includes my handwritten signature!
夏のね、7月の誕生日、ぶり、えーと、AZKi頑張ってサイン書きますので、ぜひぜひご購入してくれたら嬉しいです！
Since my birthday back in July... I'll work hard to sign them, so I'd be super happy if you'd purchase one!
そして、ちょっと気になる皆さん、EPの、はい、こちら
And for those of you curious about the EP,
えーと、内容なんですけれど、今日のねライブタイトルにもなっておりますが、
the contents—which also serve as today's live title—
「Pages」ね、今日こう今までのお歴史を、えーとなんだろな、こうページにしたという意味で、
is "Pages," meaning that I've turned my history up to now into pages.
今回AZKiの今まで、今年出しました、えー本日歌唱もしております、「afterglow」「petrichor」「canopus」「equal」の4曲と、
This time, it includes 4 songs released this year that I also sang today: "afterglow," "petrichor," "canopus," and "equal,"
ボーナス トラックの「Creating World Acoustic Arrange」合わせて5曲が収録されています。
plus the bonus track "Creating World (Acoustic Arrange)," making 5 tracks in total.
内容はですね、こちらのね楽曲のCDと、えっとブックレット、
The contents include the CD with these songs, a booklet,
歌詞カードがついております。
and a lyric card.
そしてなんと、えっとブックレットには、ここだけのイコール暗号解説…暗号があります！
And what's more, the booklet includes an "equal" cipher explanation—there's a cipher!
イコール、えっと暗号解説もついてきます！
The "equal" cipher explanation is included too!
ということで今日のね「Pages」ライブの記念に、いかがでしょうか、よろしくお願いします！
So what do you think, in commemoration of today's "Pages" live? Please check it out!
そして、もちろん単品個別販売もございます！
And of course, individual items will also be available!
ラバーマットは、こちらEPやポストカードと同じくチェキ先生の描き下ろし！
The rubber mat features new illustrations by Chee-sensei, just like the EP and postcard!
かわいい！実はこの今までのAZKiのね、あのファースト、セカンド、サードの衣装と、あと、あのアイドル衣装のAZKiが、なんと散りばめられております。
So cute! Actually, AZKi's 1st, 2nd, and 3rd outfits, as well as her idol outfit, are all scattered across it.
はい、そしてTシャツは、フリーサイズで着やすいものとなっております！AZKiがちょっとクロージに、このAZKiのロゴがいい感じになっているデザインをちょっと選ばせていただきました。
Yes, and the T-shirt is a comfortable free size! I chose a design where the AZKi logo looks really nice against the black background.
はい、というわけで、そして次、ロゴアクリルキーホルダーということでAZKiのロゴもなんと新しくなりました！このね、衣装に合わせて作っていただきました！
Right, and next, the logo acrylic key holder! AZKi's logo has also been newly updated! It was made to match this outfit!
約10センチぐらいの大きさなので、ちょうど手のひら一平大きめサイズです！ぜひぜひつけていただけたら嬉しいです！
It's about 10 centimeters in size, so it's a bit larger than the palm of your hand! I'd be so happy if you attach it to things!
というわけで、AZKi活動4周年記念グッズこのあと21時から概要欄にも貼りますのでぜひぜひよろしくお願いいたします！
So, my 4th anniversary merchandise will be on sale starting at 9:00 PM tonight, and the link will be in the description box, so please check it out!
はあ、ということで、えー、なんと告知も終わりまして、
Whew, so with the announcements finished,
楽しい時間は早いもので、次の曲で最後になります。
time flies when you're having fun, and the next song will be the last one.
え、今日はですね、みんなAZKiと11月15日、2018年の11月15日に活動を始めて今日2022年のえ、11月15日え、まる4周年ですね。
Today, everyone, having started my activities on November 15, 2018, today on November 15, 2022, marks my 4th anniversary.
AZKiと一緒に、えっと4周年を向かえてくれて、本当本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for celebrating my 4th anniversary with me!
え、みんながこうやって応援してくれるから、今日AZKiはこのステージに立ってますし、え新ビジュアルという素敵なね、あの衣装と、
Because everyone supports me like this, AZKi is standing on this stage today, and I've received such wonderful things like this new visual costume
そしてこのね、もう素敵なあのものを頂いてしまって、本当にみんなが、あのなんか色々くじけそうになったこともあるんですけど、
and this amazing stage. Honestly, there were times when I felt like giving up,
でもそれでも、うんと、なんだろうな、こうホロライブに来て、え、こうやって温かく迎えてもらって、あの歌をね歌ったり音楽を作ったりこれからも頑張って行きたいと思っておりますので
but even so, coming to Hololive and being welcomed so warmly, singing songs and creating music—I want to keep doing my best moving forward.
これからのも5年目も明日から5年目ですね。5年目もどうぞ応援よろしくお願いします！
So starting tomorrow, it's already my 5th year! Please continue to support me in my 5th year as well!
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you truly so much!
ということで 、えー最後の曲 、聞いてください。
And now, please listen to the final song:
Creating world (Acoustic Ver.)
この扉の向こうが
If what lies beyond this door
未開の可能性なら
is unmapped potential,
今を動かせるの？
can we set the present in motion?
暗闇を手探りで
Groping through the darkness,
不安と焦燥の中で 零れる光を見た
I saw a glimpse of light amid anxiety and panic.
手を伸ばして
Reaching out my hand—
この未来はキミのものだから
this future is yours.
時間を超えて繋がるよ
Connected across time,
ココロが今 創造するの
my heart is now creating
私のストーリー
my story.
声を聞かせて
Let me hear your voice;
キミを知りたいから
I want to know you.
輝かせよう 新しい世界
Let's make a new world shine bright!
生まれた意味を見つけるのさ
I'm finding the meaning of being born.
全てが始まる この場所で
In this place where everything begins—
声が枯れるまで叫んで
shouting until my voice grows hoarse.
言葉に傷つけられ
Wounded by words,
悲しみがこぼれるのは 弱いからじゃないよ
sadness spilling over isn't a sign of weakness.
勇気はここにあるから
Courage is right here,
掻き消されちゃ駄目なんだ
so you mustn't let it be wiped away.
キミはキミのままでいい
You can just be yourself.
声を上げて
Raise your voice!
私達の歌は壊れない
Our song will never break.
何度だって伝えるよ
I'll convey it to you no matter how many times.
ココロが今 共鳴するの
Our hearts are now resonating,
私のストーリー
my story.
名前を呼んで
Call my name;
そばにいるから
you're right by my side.
音を奏でよう 新しい世界
Let's play music in a new world!
キミに出会うために生きているんだ
I'm living just to meet you.
この場所が奇跡だから
Because this place is a miracle,
リアルの向こうを越えて繋ぐよ
we connect across the real.
さあ
Now...
夜は深く眠りに落ちて
Night falls into deep slumber,
やがて光が世界を照らすよ
and soon light illuminates the world.
キミに出会えたこと 意味を見つけたのさ
I found the meaning of being able to meet you,
ともに分かち合って生きたい
wanting to live on, sharing it together.
創造するの
Creating...
私のストーリー
my story.
声を聞かせて
Let me hear your voice;
キミを知りたいから
I want to know you.
開拓するの 新しい世界
Pioneering a new world!
嘘じゃないんだ
It's not a lie—
キミとのストーリー
a story with you.
全てが始まる この場所で
Everything begins right in this place,
歌を歌い続けるよ
and I'll keep on singing.
AZKi 新ビジュアルお披露目 4th Anniversary Live “Pages”
AZKi New Visual Reveal - 4th Anniversary Live "Pages"